# SHREYAS SHANKAR CHORGE

Mumbai, Maharashtra, India • +91-9920754909 • shreyaschorge81@gmail.com •

https://www.linkedin.com/in/shrevas-chorge-3a91091a2/ • Github: https://www.github.com/Shrevaschorge/

#### INTRODUCTION

Shreyas is currently a budding Software Engineer with a strong programming background and experience of using Node, js, React, js, AWS. He follows the TDD approach while developing applications. He is passionate about Web Development, Cloud Computing and has a track record of maintaining consistent performance levels and achieving the desired targets through relentless hard-work and dedication. In his free time he likes to watch TV Shows and Anime.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### 1. Plant-for-the-Planet – Munich, Bavaria, Germany March 2022 – Present

Software Engineer (Full-time)

- Successfully developed a Proof of Concept (POC) for the Fire-alerts application using various technologies such as Kafka, Express, Postgres, NASA APIs, and hosted it on Heroku Apache Kafka.
- Implemented App-level Multi-tenancy, ensuring the application can handle multiple tenants securely and efficiently.
- Implemented rate-limited APIs to control the rate of incoming requests, ensuring fair usage and preventing abuse of server resources. This proactive approach enhances the application's stability, security, and overall performance.
- Created APIs using tRPC and NextJS, leveraging technologies like Prisma and MySQL, to provide robust and performant server-side functionalities.
- Integrated Boleto Payment Method with Stripe, enabling users to make secure and seamless payments within the application.
- Designed and developed an Analytics Dashboard, utilizing Apexcharts for visually appealing graphs, and implemented serverless NodeJS for efficient API development.
- Implemented comprehensive error handling techniques, including error normalization strategies on the client-side, enhancing the application's reliability and user experience.
- Configured MUI5 and utilized styled-components to ensure a modular and maintainable CSS structure for the application.
- Implemented the OG-image feature, which allows the application to generate snapshots of the UI for a given URL, facilitating enhanced social media sharing and previews.
- Enhanced the application's global state management (Context API ReactJs) by adding type support and implementing memoization for improved performance.
- Gained experience in React Native by working on basic implementations, expanding the skillset and exploring new possibilities for cross-platform mobile app development.

## 2. Palnesto – Secunderabad, Telangana, India December, 2021 – February 2022

Software Engineer (Full-time)

- Developed responsive cross-platform (web, desktop) Front-end using Nextron Js.
- Independently developed Front-end while working with the backend team.
- Developed an online POS System for restaurants to manage their sales (Next.js, Node.js, Sequelize ORM, Postgres)
- Setup CI/CD pipeline (Jenkins, Docker)
- Created a custom theme on top of Ant Design.

# 3. Futops – Pune, Maharashtra, India September, 2021 – December, 2021

React Developer (Full-time)

- Worked on a Japanese Govt. project that analyzed and detected traffic mobility. Since security was a major concern, all activities were conducted within the intranet. I implemented offline maps to give real-time geo-location snapshots and other details. (Leaflet.js)
- Implemented Front-end pagination.
- Setup project from scratch and Implemented Authentication and authorization using JWT.
- Setup servers from scratch on the intranet and deployed dockerized containers.

React Developer Intern (Full-time)

- Implemented CoffeeConnect Feature which sends a reminder to 2 people connected on slack to have a chat. (React.js, Ant Design, Redux)
- Integrated Frontend with REST API

## 5. Headstrait Software – Mumbai, Maharashtra, India July, 2019 – Nov, 2019

UI/UX Developer Intern (Full-time)

- Designed Mobile UI for a digital wallet platform. (Invision Studio)
- Developed UI in React Js

#### 6. Personal Experience

FullStack Developer

- Used JEST with supertest for Testing APIs.
- Classic AWS (EC2, EBS, ASG, Route53, ECR, S3)

#### **PROJECTS**

#### • Zone

Zone is a C2C platform, build with scalability and availability in mind. It is built on the idea of loosely coupled microservices and keeping the server cost to a minimum.

Messaging system used is NATS.

NATS Jetstream is used for persisting messages.

- Developed REST APIs in Sanic and Flask
- Access and refresh tokens are used for authentication.
- Implemented NATS Jetstream.
- Used Docker for containerization.
- Used Kubernetes for container orchestration.

Github Link: https://github.com/Shreyaschorge/Zone

#### Novice

Novice is a Student Management Application that shares a one-to-many relationship between students and their mentor, used by a mentor to manage their students.

- Developed REST APIs in NodeJS
- Used JEST with supertest for Testing APIs.
- Used ReactJs for UI
- Configured Nginx as a proxy server
- Setup travisCI for CI/CD

Github Link: <a href="https://github.com/Shreyaschorge/Novice">https://github.com/Shreyaschorge/Novice</a>

#### **EDUCATION**

# University of Mumbai, Mumbai Bachelor of Engineering (B.E.), Information Technology, CGPI 7.69/10

2017

# NES Jr. College, Bhandup, Mumbai HSC. Science, 81.69%

Lions Pioneer English School, Matunga, Mumbai 2015

SSC, 84.00%

#### TRAINING & CERTIFICATIONS

• IBM Docker Essentials